# Jeff Doan

Denver, Colorado, United States



the.jeffdoan@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/the-jeff-doan



https://hire.jefff.co/

## Summary

I'm a Denver-based product + business designer and developer. I have 16+ years of UX/UI design, product, and development experience (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, PHP) experience. In my career, I've worked across B2C, B2B, SaaS, and mental health. I enjoy designing for conversion, driving customer & business value, optimizing onboarding to be effective, and simplifying pains with better tooling.

As a product designer, I walk the line between empathy for the user, technical constraint, and business value. I'm typically writing in Google Docs, on a call with a customer, pixeling in Figma, digging into data, or coding in Sublime Text.

I've helped businesses reduce churn, increase trial & paid sign ups, optimize feature adoption, set up research & testing processes, create feedback loops, and more. How can I help your business?

### **Experience**

#### Lead Product Designer / Design Manager

**Thriveworks** 

Oct 2021 - Jun 2023 (1 year 9 months)

- Reduced clinician churn by 17% by researching onboarding processes and providing actionable steps to improve (downstream growth impact: less \$\$ spent on recruiting, happier clinicians lead to happier, longer-term clients)
- Increased first-session show rate 30% by redesigning the post-booking reminder flow
- Decreased client cancels by 8%
- Decreased insurance billing issues (i.e. rejections) 20% by redesigning support agent flow
- Optimizing the mental health journey, and trying to make therapists' lives easier + need less technology
- Defined & led UX research process (script, calls, recruitment, recapping, opportunity synthesis)
- Defined & led UX testing process (tools, problem/opportunity to solve, testing setup, recruitment, recapping, opportunity synthesis)
- Lead UX research calls for therapists and clients by understanding their Jobs-to-be-Done
- I pioneered the clinician centric design thinking model: It was about simplicity for them, not complexity
- Designed & validated new tools to streamline therapists daily jobs to increase productivity, satisfaction, and retention
- Led design team weekly reviews, oversaw design system, and set up usability testing

## Senior Product Designer, Growth

Productboard

May 2021 - Oct 2021 (6 months)

- Defined and setup SEO strategy
- Defined continuous research strategy

- Led research and strategy for updated homepage storytelling

#### Director of Growth Design

#### SimplePractice

Sep 2019 - May 2021 (1 year 9 months)

- Increase trial-to-paid activation rate by 25%
- Manage growth product roadmap to focus on high-impact efforts with limited resources
- Increase visit-to-trial sign up conversion by 9%
- Redesigned, rebuilt, and relaunched simplepractice.com to optimize for conversions
- Manage website team with 2 senior engineers and SEO specialist, to optimize for performance & conversions

#### Senior Product Designer

#### **SimplePractice**

Jul 2017 - Sep 2019 (2 years 3 months)

- A mishmash of making the experience better while maintaining key business goals
- Helping define product strategy, writing user stories, and leading UX research

## Senior UX/UI Designer

DogVacay (Acquired by Rover, March 2017)

Oct 2016 - Jul 2017 (10 months)

- Search filter persistence: when a guest enters filter criteria, this persists until they change it (even on subsequent site visits)—led to an increase in engagement and conversion
- Desktop geolocation: get specific lat/long of desktop users for better search results—led to an increase in conversion
- Host application flow: reduce UI clutter and focus on conversion goals—led to an increase in high quality hosts and conversion
- Checkout optimizations: simplify UI, reduce confusion by re-ordering form fields—led to an increase in conversion
- Mobile Search Result optimizations: add distance from Host & sort filters based on impact—led to an increase conversions
- Host Review optimizations: simplify UI, reduce confusion by re-ordering form fields—led to an increase in conversion
- New vertical work: researching, prototyping and building custom flows for expanding revenue

## T Product Designer

#### Tradesy

Jan 2015 - Aug 2016 (1 year 8 months)

- Mobile web navigation: redesigned and built new navigation to kill the —led to deeper, longer site sessions
- Mobile + tablet signup / login: redesigned and built new pattern for simpler use—led to more conversions
- Self-service: researched, designed and built custom Zendesk integration on tradesy.com via their API —freed up Member Care team to tackle bigger member issues
- Mobile + tablet shopping filters: researched, designed and built new filter patterns

- Promoted Listings: researched, designed, and prototyped first non-commission revenue stream—ongoing effort
- In-app Notifications: designed and built framework for system in-app notifications
- Cookie consolidation: built name/key object cookie support to reduce the number of cookies we use overall
- Built JavaScript controller to handle all inline form validations (Github gist explaining front-end markup)
- Performance improvements: across the board—HTML, CSS and image optimization strategies
- Built personalized email recommendations template / custom image gallery email
- Designed & built personalized mobile web homepage concept

## .

#### Lead UX/UI Designer

#### LeagueApps

Sep 2013 - Dec 2015 (2 years 4 months)

- The whole shebang: stakeholder interviews, user testing, usability testing, wireframing, UX & UI design, front-end build & JSP integration
- Designed and built front-end mobile framework for LeagueApps-powered sites (16m+ uniques / year and growing), which works on iOS, Android and Windows
- Designed and built LeagueApps-sent emails work in all email clients & Gmail on mobile
- Redesigned the leagueapps.com marketing site to improve conversions for our unique marketshare rethinking how the SaaS platform sales cycle should be presented to prospects (not launched before I transitioned)



#### CSS Developer

#### nclud

Jul 2011 - Sep 2013 (2 years 3 months)

- Developed usable, optimized, speedy websites for multiple clients—[some design], front-end coding & templates for Ruby on Rails / Java / WordPress / ExpressionEngine / Codeigniter CMS integrations
- Designed/built Facebook apps
- Led the design & development of mobile-specific template module for our open-source Ruby on Rails CMS: BrowserCMS
- Led card-sorting & conducted user-testing for client sites
- Created HTML prototypes / for IA testing
- Spoke & didn't voice crack at multiple events

#### Senior Interactive Designer

Thinkdesign and Communications Inc.

Feb 2010 - Jul 2011 (1 year 6 months)

- Developed usable, optimized websites for multiple clients—wireframing, design, front-end coding, and CMS integrations
- Designed and developed HTML emails for national / international campaigns—wireframing, design, coding, and testing
- Designed banner ads via animated gifs before it was cool
- Created and implemented client PPC campaigns

#### **ZZMGI eMarketing Manager**

#### Marketing General Incorporated

Apr 2008 - Feb 2010 (1 year 11 months)

- Developed micro-sites for national campaigns—design, wireframing, and front-end coding
- Developed HTML emails for national / international campaigns—wireframing, design, coding, and testing
- Developed promotional, trigger-based, and newsletter HTML emails
- Designed banner ads via animated gifs before it was cool
- Managed team with senior developer

## Junior Web Designer

Sit4Less.com

Feb 2005 - Apr 2008 (3 years 3 months)

Developed email and banner ads for national campaigns wireframing, design, coding, and testing

- Developed landing pages for national and local campaigns

## Designer

**Healthy Back Store** 

Feb 2005 - Apr 2008 (3 years 3 months)

- Developed direct mail for national campaigns
- Designed ROP for national newspaper & magazine publications such as The Washington Post, The San Diego Tribune, The Wall Street Journal, and The Boston Globe
- Worked closely with vendors managing multiple print jobs
- Managed team with junior designer

## Junior Graphic Designer

Rocket9 Design

Feb 2005 - Sep 2005 (8 months)

- Created t-shirts, retooled website, developed direct mail

#### **Education**

## James Madison University

B.S, Studio Art

2001 - 2004

Studied Fine Arts, and focussed on printmaking.

#### Skills

UI Design • Experience Design • Keyword Research • A/B Testing • Prototyping • Growth Strategies

Data Analysis
Email Strategy
Mobile Design
Marketing